《雙螺旋》前情提要
Previously on Helix...
你什么時候知道自己長了腫瘤的
How long have you known about your tumor?
你嗑藥了嗎
Are you high?
我有點偏頭痛  所以吃了...
I had a migraine, so I took--
別騙我  除非你把整瓶都吃了
You're lying, unless you took the whole bottle.
我不想變得像那些怪物一樣
I don't want to become one of those things.
你知道我是什么意思
You know what I'm asking.
謝謝
Thank you.
-他還有多久時間  -好好把握這最后的機會吧
- How long does he have? - Take this time and make the most of it.
被感染的征狀之一就是出現幻覺
Hallucinations are one of the symptoms of the infection.
這他媽根本不是意外
This wasn't a goddamn accident!
這是我對你那條消息的回復
I've got a reply for that message!
第六日
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：愛卿遛小鳥  圈圈  章魚埃克斯  蘇葉夏桑
翻譯：莉莉絲  DustD  木淺薰  抹茶咖啡
時間軸：全家筒  Jessie
初校：米小勒  胖兔純
后期：MythCreator   總監：米小勒  胖兔純
姓名  朵琳·博伊爾博士
對不起  朵琳
I'm sorry, Doreen.
我們并肩作戰
We fought through...
七次疾病爆發
seven outbreaks together,
我一直以為是我在引領著你
and I always thought I was the one leading you.
而事實上是你一直在鞭策著我進步
It turns out you were the one pushing me.
找到拜耶塞羅了嗎
Have you located Balleseros?
還沒有
No, not yet.
朵琳遇害不是巧合
Doreen's murder was no coincidence.
-我不懂你什么意思  -你懂得很
- I'm not sure I follow. - Oh, you follow just fine.
不過我還是把話說明白吧
But let me spell it out for you anyway:
無論拜耶塞羅是什么陰謀
whatever Balleseros is up to,
都絕對跟這個病毒有關
it has everything to do with this virus.
你要裝作毫不知情的樣子  你隨意
If you want to pretend you don't know that, that's fine.
但我要找到他
But I want him found.
這是誰
Who's this?
瑞伊·范·艾根醫生
Dr. Rae Van Eigem.
R層封鎖后  我在B層找到了她
I found her on Level B after Level R was sealed off.
她在昏迷之前就已經死亡了
She died before the coma could set in.
你在B層找到的她
You found her on Level B?
怎么不通知我
Why wasn't I notified?
時間緊迫
There wasn't time.
我隔離了她  盡量滿足她的需求
I isolated her and tended to her needs as best I could.
這是納爾維克B
This is NARVIK-B.
她應該是帶菌者  而不是尸體
She should be a vector, not a corpse.
她怎么死的  莎拉
How did she die, Sarah?
嗎啡過量
Morphine - overdose.
誰給的藥
Who administered the dose?
我做了我認為正確的事
I did what I thought was right.
你那套不殺感染者理論也不過如此嘛  博士
So much for not killing the infected, right, Doc?
我要去R層
I am going down to Level R
帶沃克博士回來
and I am bringing back Dr. Walker.
你也許想通知你上司
You might want to inform your boss.
他在處理緊急事件
He's dealing with an emergency situation.
還有什么事能比這場病毒爆發
What emergency situation could possibly be more pressing
更緊急
than this outbreak?
他辦完事就會回來
He'll be back when he's finished,
誰都不許去R層
and no one is going down to Level R
出入都不行  包括沃克博士
no one in, no one out. That includes Dr. Walker.
你要向我開槍嗎  丹尼爾
You're gonna shoot me, Daniel?
是想這么做嗎
Is that really your play here?
你得回實驗室
You need to get back to your lab.
我不為你做事
I don't work for you!
你到底知不知道現在什么情況
Do you have any idea what this thing is?
這病毒對人有什么影響
What it's doing to people?
我很清楚  他們病了
I'm aware, yes. People are sick.
不是病了  是快死了
Not sick; they're dying!
你弟有好轉的跡象
Your brother is showing signs of improvement.
我弟幾乎沒有腦部活動
My brother barely has brain activity,
跟畑宏真是一點關系都沒有
no thanks to Hatake!
我和畑博士跟你們目的一致
Dr. Hatake and I both want the same thing you do.
你手里的槍可不是這么說的  孩子
That gun in your hand is telling a different story, son!
你倆能消停會兒嗎
Will you two cut it out?
回去做你的工作
Get... back to work.
就現在
Now.
交給我吧
I'll take care of her.
彼得
Peter.
你來這里干什么
What are you doing here?
我是來幫你的
I came to help you.
幫我什么  你...
Help me with what? You...
你不是真實存在的
You're not real.
感覺很真實啊
Feels pretty real.
走開
Go away.
我還在呢
Still here.
你讓我留下肯定是有原因的
You must want me to stay for a reason.
什么原因
Like what?
她是誰
Who is she?
你好
Hello?
雙螺旋
第一季第六集
-那現在怎么辦  -我下去找茱莉亞
- So, what now? - I'm going down to get Julia.
-等等  那...  -她寫過一本書
- Wait, what about-- - She wrote the book
是關于病毒拼接和RNA結合蛋白的
on viral splicing and RNA binding proteins.
我需要她  我們需要她
I need her - we need her -
來一起攻克這個難題
to fight this thing.
艾倫  我們不清楚她現在的病情
Alan, we don't know how sick she is.
我們甚至都不清楚她能否正常工作
We don't even know if she can work.
我們是不知道  但是朵琳死了
No, we don't. But Doreen is dead,
拜耶塞羅失蹤了
Balleseros has gone missing,
所以我們又回到原點了
and we are back to square one.
茱爾斯是我們最大的希望
Jules is our best hope.
-也是唯一的希望  -那我們怎么去R層
- She's our only hope. - How do we get down to Level R?
樓梯井被封了  電梯又被丹尼爾控制著
The stairwells are sealed shut and Daniel controls the elevator.
我得再想辦法
I'll have to improvise.
對了  給你這個  治你的偏頭痛的
By the way, these are for you, for your migraines.
加巴噴丁  你哪里...
Gabapentin. Where did you--
是蘇勒瑪尼博士用來治療強迫癥的  應該管用
Dr. Sulemani used them for OCD. They should work.
不要再用嗎啡了
No more morphine.
知道了嗎  我需要你保持敏銳機警
All right? I need you sharp.
現在就剩下我們倆了  如果我們不同心協力
You and I are all we have left. If we don't have each other,
如果我們不互相幫助  我們就一無所有了
if we don't back each other up, we have nothing.
當然了  還有...
Absolutely. And...
謝謝你
thank you.
自助餐廳開放
Cafeteria is now open.
自助餐廳...
Cafeteria is now--
天哪
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What is it?
-你的傷口  -感染了嗎
- Your wound. - Infection?
不是  傷口愈合的非常快
No, it's... it's healing remarkably fast.
肯定是因為我基因好
Must have good genes.
肯定是的
Must have.
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
你為什么不告訴我
Why didn't you tell me?
告訴你什么
Tell you what?
告訴我我出現幻覺了  杰伊不是真的
That I was hallucinating! That Jaye wasn't real.
你為什么要讓我繼續相信她的存在
Why did you let me go on believing she was here?
你很喜歡看別人受罪煎熬嗎
Do you enjoy watching people suffer?
我跟你一樣  也是名醫生
I am a doctor first, like you.
我的責任是救死扶傷
My job is to save people.
用撒謊救死扶傷嗎
By lying to them?
我沒告訴你是因為沒這個必要
I didn't tell you, because I didn't need to.
你當時不知所措
You were disoriented,
跟杰伊說話好像對你有所幫助
and speaking to Jaye seemed to be helping.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你說得對
You're right.
救命啊
Help!
救命
不要
No!
并不是誰都有機會得救的
Not everyone can be saved.
沃克博士
Dr. Walker?
茱莉亞
Julia!
Julia.
我很久沒做過鋁熱劑了
It's been a long time since I've made thermite.
上次做還是高中做惡作劇的時候
It was in high school - senior prank.
雖然過程不是很順利
It didn't go very well.
這里沒設置隔離帶
This was no quarantine;
像是被遺忘的塵封區域
it was a "seal and forget."
里面很暗  我看不太清楚
Dark in there. I can't see much.
他們可能全擠在實驗室里了
They're probably all huddled in the labs.
這樣肯定找不著她
We'll never find her like this.
我們得進去看看
We have to go inside.
我好像看見有什么人站在走廊那頭
I think I see something at the end of the hall.
快跑
Go!
-讓我看看  -艾倫  不用  我沒事
- Come here. - Alan, stop. I'm fine.
如果有任何擦傷或者創口之類的
If there's an abrasion or a cut or anything of the kind--
-真沒事  -我們得確保無虞  你明白的
- I'm fine. - We have to make sure. You know that.
我真是沒想到有這么多人
I had no idea there'd be so many of them.
讓你面臨這么大的危險  我真是昏頭了
I ought to have my head examined for putting you at risk.
是我自愿跟著你下來的
I chose to go down there with you.
聽著  先是朵琳  現在又是茱爾斯
Listen, first Doreen, then Jules.
我可不能再失去你了  莎拉
I can't lose you too, Sarah.
茱莉亞的事我們要怎么辦
what are we gonna do about Julia?
為了找到她  我們得先對付那些...
To get to her, we have to go through those...
-那些怪物  -我想說"那些患者"
- Those monsters? - I was going to say "those patients."
危重患者  我們要想幫助茱爾斯
desperately sick patients. If we want to get to Jules,
我們得先治好他們
we'll have to treat them first.
要是治不好呢
What if we can't?
那上頭就得連同我們一起
Then they'll bury this base...
將這基地徹底摧毀
with us in it.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
你昏過去了
You passed out.
別擔心  茱莉亞
Don't worry, Julia.
用不了多久我就能治好你
We'll have you back on your feet in no time.
你照我眼睛做什么  我看不清了
What are you doing to my eyes? I can't see.
那是什么
What is that?
我要給你打鎮靜劑
I'm giving you a sedative.
你需要休息
You should sleep.
我不想睡過去
I don't want to sleep.
別說話
Shh.
你會好起來的
You're going to be OK.
準許進入
Access granted.
怎么回事
Aw! What the hell?
-你是誰  -我還想問你呢
- Who are you? - I could ask you the same thing.
我是阿娜娜
I'm Anana.
阿娜娜
Anana?
我這是在哪
Where am I?
你在我家里
You're in my home.
非得銬起來嗎
Are these really necessary?
鬼知道你是誰呀
Don't know you from Adam.
要換了是我  沒準也會把你銬起來
In that case, maybe I should cuff you too.
我叫塞爾西奧
I'm Sergio.
我估計著我臉上這一拳是拜你所賜
I assume I have you to thank for punching me in the face?
你一個勁地打我
You kept trying to fight me.
你感覺怎么樣了  賽爾西奧
How are you feeling otherwise,Sergio?
糟糕透頂
Like hell.
那也比被扔在雪地里
That's better than expected for a guy
等著被凍死要強得多
who was left for dead on the ice.
-這綠乎乎的是什么玩意  -這是海藻藥膏
- What is this green shit? - It's a seaweed pack.
這附近又找不著什么神醫  所以將就著吧
We're not exactly near the Mayo Clinic, so relax.
你是個警察
You're the law?
是湯拉爾定居點周圍四百英里以內的的治安官
Only peace officer within 400 miles of Tonrar settlement.
-湯拉爾嗎  -意思是"惡鬼"
- Tonrar? - Means "Ghost."
其實沒有名字說的這么嚇人
Sounds scarier than what it is.
我們不在一個地點停留太久
We don't stay in one place very long.
給  喝了這個  能讓你暖和點
Here, drink this. It'll warm you up.
你手指頭沒凍掉真是運氣太好...
You're lucky to have all your fingers and--
你這是想干什么
What'd you have to do that for,huh?
我可是盡了地主之誼呢
I was trying to be hospitable.
-疼  -疼就對了  正好讓你明白狀況
- It hurts. - Good! Let that be our introduction.
你見鬼去吧
Bullshit!
-怎么著  你想拿我當人質嗎  -看情況
- What am I, a hostage? - Depends.
局面會有多難看  全在你
This can be as dirty as you want it to be.
-你想要什么  -要你腦袋里的
- What do you want? - I want what's in here.
告訴我所有關于北極生物公司的事
Tell me what you know about Arctic Biosystems.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
你想這么玩嗎
That's how you want to play it?
那好  或許你就該是人質
All right, then maybe you are a hostage.
-真是荒唐  -如果你配合  那是最好
- This is ridiculous! - If you want to talk, great.
如果不  我總有辦法把你帶回基地
If not, I can always bring you back to the base
讓那些想殺你的人了結你  有始有終
and let whoever tried to kill you finish off what they started.
莎拉  來看這個
Sarah...come have a look at this.
說說你看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
病毒在侵害細胞  迅速繁殖
The virus is attacking the cell, multiplying rapidly.
再看看  仔細看
Look again. Look more closely.
天哪
Oh, my god.
之前我居然沒發現
I can't believe I didn't see it before.
你怎么能發現呢  我們根本沒注意這方面
How could you have? We weren't looking for it.
他把病毒用作運載機制
He's using the virus as a delivery mechanism.
問題是  病毒對基因組有什么影響
The question is: what's the virus bringing to the party?
原因又是什么
And why?
狗娘養的
Son of a bitch.
-法拉格特博士  -病毒里有什么
- Dr. Farragut. - What's in the virus?
-什么也沒有  -我親眼看到了
- Nothing. - I saw it with my own eyes.
你在基因序列中加入了什么
What did you splice into its genetic code?
我聽不懂你在說什么
I don't know what you mean.
我知道你把病毒用作運載機制
I know you're using the virus as a delivery mechanism.
告訴我  你亂用的是哪種基因療法
Now, what kind of gene therapy are you messing with?
你把我弟弟當成了小白鼠
You used my brother as a lab rat!
你搞砸了他的生活  茱莉亞的生活
You played with his life, with Julia's life,
還搞砸了R層那些可憐人的生活
with the rest of those poor people on Level R.
你把基地建在這兒就沒人能監管你
You put this place here so you wouldn't be regulated,
然后你就可以扮演上帝來操控別人的生活
so you could play God with people's lives!
看看你帶來的后果吧
Look where's it's gotten you!
告訴我真相
Tell me the truth.
是的  納爾維克的確是個運載系統
Yes...NARVIK is a... delivery system.
但法拉格特博士  這并不是陰謀
But there is no conspiracy, Dr. Farragut.
陰謀論只是你幻想出來的
That, I'm afraid, is in your head.
至于你弟弟...他也不是小白鼠
As far as your brother... he was no lab rat.
那這到底是怎么回事
What then? What is all this?
這是治療絕癥的一種方式
A way to treat what was once untreatable.
癌癥
Cancer.
世衛組織定義五大絕癥包括艾滋病  惡性腫瘤
白血病  類風濕  肌萎縮側髓硬化癥
化解全部"五大絕癥"  試想一下
All five classifications. Think of it:
這能治愈當代的一種最致命疾病
a cure for one of the deadliest diseases of our time.
病毒不用來害人而是是用來救人
Instead of causing harm, the virus delivers a cure.
真是妙點子
It's brilliant.
不幸的是  我們還沒有完善它
Unfortunately, we haven't perfected it yet.
這不是病毒
It wasn't the virus.
不是嗎
What's not?
病毒讓彼得生病  但并沒有改變他
The virus made Peter sick but it didn't change him.
是病毒內的基因療法改變了他
It was the gene therapy inside the virus.
你在納爾維克-B菌株里加了什么才改變了他
What did you put into the NARVIK-B strain that changed him?
沒加什么
Nothing.
我們還沒有使用基因療法
We hadn't introduced the gene therapy.
病毒里有其它東西
There is something inside this virus.
我會找出來的
And I will find it.
你得告訴我這到底怎么回事
I need you to tell me what's really going on here.
不關你的事
It doesn't concern you.
我唯一關心的就是你和基地的安全
Your safety and the safety of this base is my only concern.
我被蒙在鼓里就保護不了你
I can't protect you if I'm in the dark.
你不在的時候發生了很多事情
A lot has happened while you were away.
拜耶塞羅找到了威特博士
Balleseros found Dr. Hvit. -
-什么  他是怎么...  -沒事了
- What? How did he-- - it's not a problem.
我已經把他解決了
I took care of him. -
解決了他  你干了什么
Took care of him? How?
讓他見識了一下冰鎬的厲害
Introduced him to the business end of an ice axe.
并留他在冰天雪地里自生自滅
Left him out on the ice.
你到底做了什么
What have you done?
是你說過他的存在對我們是一個威脅
You said yourself he was a threat.
所以我消滅了他
I eliminated him.
你個蠢貨  難道你不知道嗎
You fool! Don't you see?!
一旦他沒及時向上級報告
When he fails to check in,
那些人就會來了
they will come.
你需要吃點東西
You need to eat.
你的身體需要能量才能恢復
Your body is trying to heal.
說得好像你在乎似的
Like you care.
你死了對我沒什么好處
You're no good to me dead.
好吧  那告訴我為什么我會在這里
Fine. I just want to know why I'm here.
所以我們又要開始兜圈子了嗎
So, we're doing this dance again?
我說過  我想知道北極生物公司的事情
I told you why you're here. Arctic Biosystems.
我也說過了  我什么都不知道
I already told you, I don't know anything.
你知道的事情多到足以讓別人對你下手
You knew enough that someone tried to shank your ass
殺人滅口了
and leave you for dead.
那是私人恩怨
That was a personal thing.
與基地無關
Had nothing to do with the base.
他們在做什么研究
What about the research they do?
還有那些孩子們
Tell me about the children.
什么孩子  你到底在胡說些什么
What children? What are you talking about?!
你不說拉倒  反正我們有的是時間
We can try this again later.
無論你怎么問  我的答案都是一樣
Gonna be the same whenever you try it.
那就要看你能挨餓到什么程度了
That depends on how hungry you get!
這個年齡的孩子多可愛啊
They are so cute at that age.
這是哪  你為什么帶我來這兒
What is this place? Why did you bring me here?
我只是來湊湊熱鬧而已
Hey, this is your dance party.
這可是屬于你的舞會
I'm just along for the ride.
也許你應該問問她
Maybe you should ask her.
問什么
About what?
或許她正試圖讓你回想起一些事情
Maybe she's trying to get you to remember something.
一些你已經忘記的事情
Something you've forgotten.
已經忘記的事情我怎么還想得起來
How am I supposed to remember something I've forgotten?
有些事情只要你不想忘記
Nothing's ever really forgotten -
就永遠不會忘
not if you don't want it to be.
去吧  去問問她
Go ahead, ask her.
你好
Hi.
我是茱莉亞
I'm Julia.
我也叫茱莉亞
That's my name too.
茱莉亞  這里是什么地方
What is this place, Julia?
這里是我家
This is my house.
你是說你住在這里嗎
You mean you live here?
只有夏天才住這里
Only in the summer.
我和媽媽一起來的
I come here with my mommy.
我小時候也是和我母親一起過夏天的
I used to spend the summer with my mommy too.
真的嗎
You did?
嗯  在一個叫蒙大拿的地方
Mm-hmm. In a place called Montana.
你聽說過這個地方嗎
Have you ever heard of it?
我當然聽過啦  傻瓜
Of course I have, silly.
我們現在不就在這兒嗎
Where do you think we are right now?
你說得對  這是我長大的地方
Yes. This is where I grew up.
這里是蒙大拿
This is Montana,
我和母親一起住過的地方
where I lived with my mother.
我回家了
I'm home.
剩下的就是等待嗎
Now we wait.
只能如此了
Something like that.
怎么回事
What the hell?
你見過...
Have you ever...
它在做什么
What's it doing?
對低溫產生了反應
Reacting to the cold.
極度低溫
Extreme low temperatures.
會減慢病毒的效果
Slowing down the effects of the virus.
這說不定在人體上也行得通
Which means this might work on humans.
我們要給彼得降溫
We need to get Peter on ice.
把他頭抬一下
Lift his head. All right.
艾倫  那到底是什么東西
Alan, what was that thing?
不管是什么  低溫能延緩它的效果
Whatever it was, the cold slowed it down.
我從沒見過像這樣的東西
I've never seen anything like that in my life.
莎拉  沒人見過這種東西
Sarah, no one has seen anything like that.
起作用了
It's working.
起作用了  但是還要繼續給他降溫
It's working, but we have to get him colder.
有個實驗室  在G層  是研究冷沉淀的
There was a lab. Down on Level G, doing some kind of cryo work.
-誰的  -威克多·艾德里安博士
- Who? - Um... Dr. Victor Adrian.
你呆在這里  持續給他降溫并準備轉移
You stay here. Get him colder and get him prepped to move.
好
OK.
鑰匙
Key.
休想
Don't.
明白了嗎
Understand?
休想
Don't!
你明白了嗎
Do you understand?!
-輕點  -想知道你為什么在這嗎  看看
- Easy! - You want to know why you're here? Take a look.
-看什么  一群小孩嗎  -失蹤兒童
- What am I looking at? A bunch of kids? - Missing kids.
過去二十年來  北極生物公司周圍
Thirty-one over the past two decades, all within
二百英里的范圍內發生了31起失蹤兒童事件
200 miles of Arctic Biosystems and your precious Dr. Hatake.
我不明白
I don't understand.
有人在偷我們的孩子
Someone's been stealing our children.
你根本不知道你保護的是什么人
You have no idea who you're protecting.
或者你知道
Or maybe you do.
你說呢
You tell me.
你再輕舉妄動  我就崩了你
You try anything again, I will shoot you.
真有趣
That's funny.
我們慢慢的從身后接近她
We'll sneak up on her slow.
我就在你后邊  別害怕
I'll be right behind you. Don't be afraid.
威克多·艾德里安嗎
Victor Adrian?
我是疾控中心的艾倫·法拉格特
I'm Alan Farragut of the CDC.
滾蛋
Piss off.
-我正看著呢  -我需要你的幫助
- I was watching that. - I need your help.
我被關在這里面都一個星期了
I've been stuck here for a week
如同困獸一般
like a caged animal.
你還指望我熱情歡迎你嗎
What do you expect me to do? Put out a welcome mat?
我知道這情況不怎么理想
I know the situation has been less than ideal.
這可真是年度最佳輕描淡寫
Now that is the understatement of the year.
我這么做有什么好處
What do I get out of it?
-你說什么  -等價交換
- Excuse me? - Quid pro quo.
我幫了你這個忙  你也得回報我
I scratch your back, you scratch mine.
-我們能達成共識嗎  -你想要什么
- Do we understand each other? - What is it you want?
首先  我要你去把守衛撤掉
First, you're gonna call off the guards.
這六天來我連拉屎
I haven't taken a shit without
都得有人監視著
a chaperone for the last six days.
其次  我要在救援到來后
Second, I want to be first in line
第一個離開這鬼地方
out of this hell-hole when the cavalry arrive.
行  只要你幫我解決這事
All right, all right. You help me solve this,
我會讓你排在第一個的
and you will be first in line.
我向你保證
I guarantee it.
艾倫·法拉格特博士
Dr. Alan Farragut,
有何能為你效勞的
how may I be of assistance?
你是研究冷卻系統的
You work with cooling systems?
冷沉淀療法
Cryo-therapy?
變頻浸沒降溫  我的最新成果
VFC Immersion. Latest and greatest.
真的有效嗎
Does it work?
不如你親自來看看吧
Why don't you say hello to some of my friends?
-給我住手  -你倆都為畑宏效力
- Stop right there! - You both work for Hatake.
-是嗎  -放開他
- Is that it?! - Let him go.
-就是他在基地要殺了我  -什么時候
- He tried to kill me back at the base! - What? When?
你想要畑宏的信息  找他就行了
You want information about Hatake? Here's your man!
來啊  問他
Go ahead! Ask him!
你瘋了嗎  這是我弟弟
Are you out of your mind?! That's my brother!
-丹尼爾是你弟弟  -丹尼爾是誰
- Daniel is your brother? - Who's Daniel?
這是我弟弟圖克
That's my brother Tulok!
能告訴我你為什么要襲擊我弟弟嗎
You want to tell me why you attacked my brother?
我只是...想逃跑
I was just... trying to escape.
這是我和弟弟們的照片
This is a picture of me and my brothers.
他們是雙胞胎
Twins.
你剛見到的是圖克
You met Tulok outside.
這個是米嘉
This is Miksa.
在我們還小時他就失蹤了
He disappeared when we were kids.
當時他只有四歲
He was only four years old.
米嘉現在在哪
Where's Miksa now?
明知故問  你這個混蛋
You tell me, you son of a bitch.
-你見過他吧  -我得回基地
- Have you seen him? - I need to go back to the base.
我要和你一起去
We need to go back to the base.
我從沒想過在人身上試驗這項技術
Look, I didn't know we'd be trying this out on an actual person,
還是一個狀況如此糟糕的人
let alone someone as bad off as he is.
-我不能保證任何東西  -明白
- I can't promise anything. - Understood.
變頻浸沒降溫
VFC immersion hypothermia.
人體臨床試驗  第一次
Human trials, take one.
你要如何抑制
How do you stop the body's
人體自身的御寒機能呢
natural defense mechanisms against the cold?
這就要靠我這套特殊的冷卻流程了
It is all in how we cool the body down.
冷卻液進入肺部的同時
The solution is taken into his lungs
也將從皮膚滲入
while it simultaneously soaks into the skin
從里到外完全包裹身體
and envelops the entire body, inside and on the out.
那他怎么維持呼吸
So how does he breathe?
他不需要呼吸
He doesn't breathe.
人體在九個月的胚胎階段就不呼吸
Humans don't breathe for the first nine months.
只要維持他的血氧即可
It's a matter of keeping him oxygenated.
成功與否你都會遵守我們的約定吧
Either way, we still have a deal right?
不論他是生是死
No matter how this goes.
再給我一點時間就好  彼得
Just give me a little more time, Peter.
開始吧
Let's do this.
茱莉亞  快來吃晚餐
Julia, come on. Time to eat.
你怎么也在這
Why are you here?
是你害她生病的  都是你的錯
You're the one that made her sick. This is all your fault.
我的錯  這怎么能怪我呢
My fault? Don't blame me.
我們都是因為她才被困在這的
We're all trapped here because of her.
-你不講道理  -誰說要講道理了
- That's not fair. - Who said anything about fair?
這是你的潛意識
This is all in your head.
問題是你讓我們來這干什么
Why are we even here?
我不知道
I don't know.
能請你遞一下蔓越莓醬嗎
Pass the cranberry sauce.
-謝謝  -所有都因你而起  茱莉亞
- Thank you - It's all about you, Julia.
一直都是
It's always been about you.
他說的沒錯
He's right, y'know. He's right.
是你讓我們陷入了這場麻煩
You got us into this mess.
我沒有  我不是  我只是
I'm not -- I mean, I didn't -- I just,
我不是故意的  拜托
I didn't mean to get -- Oh, come on.
我也想知道為什么
I just want answers.
你連真正的問題是什么都不清楚
You don't even know the right questions to ask.
為什么找你  茱莉亞
Why you, Julia?
為什么會有這種病毒  為什么現在爆發
Why this virus? Why now?
餓死了
I'm starved.
我們能邊吃邊說嗎
Can we do this while we eat?
其實你知道所有答案  只是你沒意識到罷了
You have all the answers. You just don't know it.
我在想  只是想不起來
I'm trying to remember, but I can't.
那就快想
Just figure it out already.
快想出來我們好吃飯
Figure it out so we can eat.
有人要紅薯嗎
Would anyone like sweet potatoes?
也許問題的重點不在于我們
Maybe the question isn't why we're here
而在于我們為什么會在這
as much as why are we're HERE -
在這  這個你長大的小木屋
this place, the cabin where you grew up.
也許吃點東西我們就能更快地想出答案
Maybe this would be easier if we all ate something.
你能來切火雞嗎  茱爾斯
Will you carve, Jules?
等等  不該是這樣的
Wait, this isn't supposed to be happening.
這不是真的
This is not happening!
這樣真的沒問題嗎
Are y... are you sure about this?
他會適應的
He'll adapt.
他會穩定下來的  這是正常反應
He'll settle. It's normal.
你怎么知道是正常反應
Normal for what?
沒事的  那些猴子和他的反應一樣
It's OK. The monkeys did the exact same thing.
還有老鼠也是
The rats too.
無反應
這會害死他的  艾倫
This is killing him. Alan.
艾倫
Alan!
-他要被淹死了  -不  不要
- He's drowning. - No. No.
這是我們唯一能救回他的方式了
If there's any chance we could save him...
他的體溫在下降
His core temperature's dropping.
35攝氏度
It's 95.
29度
Eighty-five.
冷卻液輸送中
24度
Seventy-five.
18度
Sixty-five.
13度
Fifty-five degrees.
艾倫
Alan.
他能看見我們嗎
Can he see us?
我想不能
No. I don't think so.
但這確實起作用了
But it's something.
有進展了
Progress.
疾控中心似乎有了突破性進展
The CDC seems to have had a breakthrough.
抱歉讓你失望了
I'm sorry for disappointing you.
-請原諒我  父親  -是我的錯
- Please forgive me, father-- - It's my fault.
是我還沒有將你準備充分
I didn't prepare you well enough.
這是我的失誤
I made a mistake.
沒什么失誤可言  只有被浪費了的機會
There are no mistakes, only opportunities wasted.
這種事不會再發生了
It won't happen again.
很好  因為我們的時間已經不多了
Good. We don't have much time to prepare.
你想讓我做什么
What do you want me to do?
首先...
First...
帶我去看看拜耶塞羅少校的尸體
show me Major Balleseros' body.
太神奇了
It's amazing.
雖然他的大腦活動還沒完全恢復
Brain activity isn't 100%,
但畢竟有所好轉了
but it's a start.
艾倫  你還好嗎
Alan, are you OK?
我就把他留在這里了
This is where I left him.
就是這里
Right here.
我脫下了他的外套和靴子
I took his jacket and boots.
他走不了多遠的
He couldn't have got far.
他是被人帶走了
He's been taken.
我去找他
I'll go find him.
不用
No.
我們晚些再處理這件事
We'll deal with this later.
他們來了
They're here.
你還好嗎
Are you OK?
是的
Yeah.
警告  有飛機駛入
Warning: incoming flight.
感謝上帝  救兵終于到了
Thank God. The cavalry's here.
怎么可能
How?
我一直沒能和外界聯系上
I never got the call out.
《雙螺旋》  下集預告
On the next Helix.
-軍隊嗎  -不是  是我的贊助商
- Military? - No, my corporate patrons.
沃克博士為什么被鎖起來了
Dr. Walker, why is she locked up?
她被感染了
She's infected.
彼得
Peter?
畑宏毀掉了他身邊所有的人
Hiroshi has destroyed everyone who has ever been close to him,
別讓他把你也毀掉
don't let him do the same to you.
薩頓是一個很危險的敵人
Sutton can be a dangerous enemy.
停下  停下
Stop it! stop it!
我想她來這的目的與我們不同
I don't think our agenda is her agenda.